We have seen a surge of generalist AI
agents recently. Powerful tools that can
automate almost anything from coding
applications to creating powerpoints to
handling research and so much more.
These agents can truly delegate our
mundane tasks and supercharge
productivity. But there's a big problem.
Most of these AI tools or agents are
locked behind pay walls or are extremely
difficult to set up locally, especially
if you want a fully open-source
generalist AI agent. That changes today,
though. I would like to introduce Lemon
AI, which is the world's first full
stack fully open-source generalist AI
agent that you can run completely
locally as well as for free with
different providers like Olama that you
can host models with. Lemon AI is an
intelligent autonomous agent that can
work alongside you to automate virtually
any task. It features an integrated code
interpreter that works through a sandbox
for safe code execution as well as
supports everything from deep research
to data analysis to web browsing all
without the cloud. It's powered by
various local models as well as whatever
API provider you would want. And LemonAI
offers various sorts of features from
planning, action, reflection as well as
memory. And it ensures complete privacy
and zero cloud dependencies. In essence,
Lemon AI is a fully local alternative to
platforms like Manis and GenSpark AI,
but are 100% free and open source. Just
take a look at this example where in
this demo, it was tasked to create a
travel plan using an MCP to create map
routes and build a custom web page. It
functions exactly like a generalist AI
agent. But something that you might not
know is that LemonAI doesn't just follow
instructions. It's capable of planning,
reflecting, and updating, and improving
at each step. And this is because of its
predefined self- evvolving capability
that's built within the agent where it
can refine any sort of itinerary or any
sort of task. and it overall enhances
any objective that was given because it
has that capability to keep improving
and working on continuous
self-improvement.
Before we get started, I just want to
mention that you should definitely go
ahead and subscribe to the world of AI
newsletter. I'm constantly posting
different newsletters on a weekly basis.
So, this is where you can easily get
up-to-date knowledge about what is
happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. Here is
another example where Lemon AI used this
deep research capability to do a market
analysis on the Apple stock. And you can
see that it has this capability built
within that it's capable of doing
locally where it can do market analysis
and data analysis thoroughly on any sort
of stock. and it's capable of outputting
something like a comparison report that
talks about the performance of the stock
as well as other detailed reports that
make it super intuitive and super easy
to get a good understanding of the data.
Now, to get started, it is super simple.
It's not like the other open-source
generalist AI agents that are super
complicated to set up. In terms of the
system requirements, you just need to
make sure you have Docker Desktop
installed on whatever operating system
you have. So, make sure you have it
installed. If you're on Windows, make
sure you have WSL and Docker Desktop
support. So, once you have installed
Docker Desktop, make sure you have it
running within the background. And once
you have it running, all you got to do
is just simply copy the Docker pull
command and just open up WSL or your
command prompt for Mac OS or for Linux.
And then now you can just simply paste
in this command within your terminal.
This will easily pull all the different
files that are needed to have Lemon AI
functional on your computer. And then
once it has finished pulling, all you
got to do is just run the Docker run
command. So just copy this component and
then paste it into your terminal. So it
looks like it has finished pulling
everything. And now I can run it with
the docker run command. So now let's
just click enter. And it should start up
on my local host. It'll then start up on
your local host. And you're going to be
able to now access it through your
browser. But the first thing you want to
do is select your model. So you can do
so by simply clicking done, then heading
over to the bottom left and clicking on
settings. This is where you can
configure things like your model
services, search services, and many
other things. So this is where you can
even use Olama to have it linked to an
open source model that you have locally
installed. But to save some time, I'm
going to be using something like the
Gemini model as well as maybe even pod
so that I can get better code
generation. But you can see that how
easy it is to easily configure
everything. It's super easy to set up
this generalist AI agent locally unlike
many of the other agents we've showcased
how to set up on our channel. But if you
want to implement other things like
having uh search services implemented
with different providers like Tavly, you
can easily configure that over here. You
can even add MCPs uh so that you can
connect other data sources. And then
there's even an experience library.
These are basically previous generations
that are already generated within Lemon
AI so that it basically helps the AI
agent better generate future
generations. But now if we go back into
the homepage, we can now work with Lemon
AI to do almost anything. And now you
can simply say, "Create me a full-on
YouTube script writing tool." Select the
model of your choice, attach any files
if needed, even attach an MCP, and then
you can send in this prompt. Now, you
can see that it is going to process it
using the Gemini 2.5 Pro, and it will
deploy multiple agents to help us
accomplish this task. Currently it looks
like planning is in process. So it's
going to work thoroughly to develop a
strategic plan to set this up so that
multiple AI agents can tackle it. So
currently it looks like it is focusing
on setting the different requirements
through the MD uh file and you can see
that it is creating that thorough
analysis on how to tackle this plan.
Phase two is where it's going to work on
information and data collection. So you
can see right now it is using the Gemini
model to source different websites as to
how it can create a full-on YouTube
scripting tool. And you can see that
right now it is thoroughly looking
through multiple sites to implement the
best strategy for script writing. And
this is where it will compile all the
contents it needs to then develop the
app for it. So it looks like the YouTube
script writer pro has been fully
developed now. And it looks absolutely
awesome. You can see that it has created
a script editor. It has also provided me
analytics on the script that you have
written. And then there's also
collaboration where you can add team
members. Obviously, this is not
connected yet because it's not something
that has been externally added with APIs
to allow others to access, but you can
preview your script over here. But now,
let's actually take a look at a project
idea that we can script up. So, just
actually take a look at this. There's
real time SEO score uh inputs which will
actually score how well your title is
and then you can add a brief description
on it. You can then add a category on
something like a tutorial, how to
reaction video, etc. You can provide a
tone and add a couple of different tags.
I simply just created the script editor
tool that would give me a score on it.
And overall, this was something that it
generated quite rapidly. If you like
this video and would love to support the
channel, you can consider donating to my
channel through the super thanks option
below. Or you can consider joining our
private Discord where you can access
multiple subscriptions to different AI
tools for free on a monthly basis, plus
daily AI news and exclusive content,
plus a lot more. But that's basically it
guys for today's video on Lemon AI. This
is a great new fullyfree local
alternative to Manis and GenSpark with
many additional feature sets that aren't
available with other generalist AI
agents. It's super easy to install and
the quality is a lot better than what we
have saw previously with local
generalist AI agents. I'll leave all
these links in the description below so
that you can easily get started. But
with that thought guys, thank you guys
so much for watching. Make sure you go
ahead and subscribe to the second
channel. This is where I'm going to be
posting a lot more. So definitely stay
tuned over here. Join the newsletter,
join our private Discord, follow me on
Twitter, and lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos because there's a
lot of content that you can truly
benefit from. But with that thought,
guys, have an amazing day, spread
positivity, and I'll see you guys really
shortly. He suffers.